Jessica Wright

Columbus, OH | 614-506-5973 | wright.983@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/jessicabwright | Portfolio Link

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Full stack developer with a passion for fostering lasting relationships between users and companies. Proven ability to manage multiple, complex projects in a team environment. Mission-driven developer looking to challenge the status-quo while building impactful products with a cool team.

TECH STACK

Java • Spring • Hibernate • JPA • JavaScript • MVC • HTML5 • CSS3 • Flexbox • Grid • TDD • Agile (Scrum) • Object Oriented Programming • AJAX • JSON • Restful APIs • Responsive Design / Mobile • SQL • Relational Databases • Source Control / Git

INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

GitHub Address

We Can Code IT, Columbus, OH

Software Developer Apprentice, 2018

github.com/jessicawright

- Immersive coding bootcamp to formalize skills in OOP, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3 and other technologies
- > Completed weekly group projects and 4 mastery projects gaining experience in full-stack development
- > Practiced pair-programming, source control, TDD and Agile methodologies

Project 1:Nightmare Hospital Game

Java console game highlighting knowledge of 4 pillars of Object Oriented Programming

Java/TDD/Agile/OOP/Git

Project 2: Virtual Pet

Java console application mimicking Tamagotchi digital pet

Java/TDD/Agile/OOP/Git

EXPERIENCE HIGHLIGHTS

The Matriots Political Action Committee (PAC)

Hive Relationship Manager, July 2018 - Dec 2018

- Integrated donor records to a new Constituent Relationship Management software system by analyzing current vs. preferred data mapping and defining report requirements. Developed suite of reports for staff use
- > Prepared and filed quarterly PAC financial reports with the Ohio Secretary of State's office
- Designed and deployed the PAC's first donor stewardship program to enhance donor loyalty

The Ohio State University Wexner Medical Center

Assistant Director, Donor Relations and Stewardship, Jan 2018 - July 2018

Oversaw project management for major donor appreciation and stewardship events for the Ross Heart Hospital and Neurological Institute

Mid-Ohio Foodbank

Donor Relations Coordinator, July 2016 - Jan 2018

- Designed content and creative strategy to manage \$1.7 million annual direct mail program; wrote direct mail and digital solicitations
- > Enhanced monthly giving program, consisting of 1,110 sustaining donors, with 18% revenue growth in FY17

Food Pantry Coordinator, June 2012 - Jan 2016

➤ Managed the largest emergency food program in central Ohio, distributing 3.1 million pounds of food to 11,264 low-income families

Agency Services Customer Service Specialist, Nov 2012 - June 2012

AmeriCorps Vista Aug 2010 - Aug 2011

EDUCATION & TRAINING

We Can Code IT: **Certificate of Software Development**, 2019 The Ohio State University: **BS**, **Microbiology**